Lumbard, Eliot H.; Papers apap071
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1956-1996; 3; 10.17 cubic ft.
  - Legislative Remedies for Corruption, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Loan Sharks, Correspondence and Newsclipping, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Local Crime Commissions, Newsclippings and Report, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Lumbard - Schedule for September, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lumbard, Special Assistant Counsel - Appointment, News Release, Memos, Notes, and Headshots, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mafia, Newsclippings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "The Mafia Talks" - Drafts and Notes, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Memo Suggesting Rockefeller Follow Nixon's Example of Strengthening Crime Control and Various Nixon Speeches, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Messages to the Legislature, and Local and State Gov't Expenditures for the Administration of Criminal Justice in NYS w/ Statistical Supplement, 1965; 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Municipal Police Training Council, Memos, Notes and Corresp., 1962-1964; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Narcotic Drugs Crime Prevention, Reports, Articles, Press Releases, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Narcotics Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The National Emergency Conference on "Citizen Action and Leadership Against Crime and Delinquency" - Emergency Conference, Program, Reports, 1967 November (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Organized Crime Intelligence Board - Proposal Sent to Oyster Bay Conference Participants, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National and Regional Crime Commissions, Articles, Corresp., and Pamphlets, 1962-1967; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Nelson A. Rockefeller Institute of Gov't Pamphlets, 1984; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NYC Crime-Reports and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - NYS Counties Police Forces, Correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - NYS Crime Control Grant Program Under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Acts, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "A NYS Dept. of Crime Control: A New Concept for Protection of Persons and Property of the Public", 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NYS Narcotics Addiction Control Commission Summary Reports, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - NYSIIS, Ad Hoc Computer Evaluation Committee Report (1 of 2), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - NYSIIS, Ad Hoc Computer Evaluation Committee Report (2 of 2), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - NYSIIS - Britain - Feasibility Report for National Police Records System, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - NYSIIS, Computer- Based Responses to the NYS Criminal Justice Community's Need to Know" Speech by EHL, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - NYSIIS, Computers and Privacy Journal Articles, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - NYSIIS -Contract Negotiations- Notes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - NYSIIS, Correspondence, General, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NYSIIS Correspondence, General, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - NYSIIS, Corresp., Reports, and Articles on Crime Data and Computers (1 of 2), 1961-1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - NYSIIS, Corresp., Reports, and Articles on Crime Data and Computers (2 of 2), 1961-1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - NYSIIS, Correspondence, Reports, and Newsclippings, 1965-1979 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - NYSIIS - Correspondence with British Officials (1 of 2), 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - NYSIIS - Correspondence with British Officials (2 of 2), 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - NYSIIS Cost Analysis (1 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - NYSIIS Cost Analysis (2 of 2), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - NYSIIS " The Cranky Godfather of the Computer", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - NYSIIS, "Crime' 68: The NYSIIS Response", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - NYSIIS, "Executive Orientation on Electronic Data Processing" Presented to Bankers Trust Company, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - NYSIIS Electronic Data Processing (1 of 2), 1960-1964; 1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - NYIIS Electronic Data Processing (2 of 2), 1960-1964; 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NYSIIS "Electronic Data Processing for the Administration of Justice Systems and the Enforcement of Law," Comments by EHL, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - NYIIS "Feasibility Report and Recommendations for a NYIIS", 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NYIIS, History, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - NYSIIS Identification Intelligence (NYSIIS) Booklets, 1987; Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - NYSIIS, "Implementation of Organized Crime Intelligence", 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NYSIIS - Job Descriptions and Appropriations, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NYSIIS, "A Lawyer's Concern w/ a Computer Installation," by F. Awalt Jr., 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NYSIIS " Model State Statute for Criminal Offender Record Information Systems" -California- Final Draft, 1971 March 3 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - NYSIIS, "Preliminary Draft of a Security and Privacy Policy", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NYSIIS Privacy on Computer Systems Reports (1 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NYSIIS, Privacy on Computer Systems Reports (2 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NYSIIS, Program Justification for the 1967-68 Budget, ca. 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - NYSIIS, "Project Status Reports", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - NYSIIS, Proposal to Study the Feasibility of Law Enforcement Officials Using Electronic Data Processing, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - NYSIIS, Proposed Security Policy Guide + NYSIIS Security Commitment, 1967; Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NYSIIS, "Recommendations to the Gov. Regarding the Administration of the Criminal Justice System", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - NYSIIS - Reports, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - NYSIIS Research (1 of 2), 1966- 1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - NYSIIS Research (2 of 2), 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NYSIIS, Rockefeller Speech on NYSIIS in Westchester, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - NYSIIS, SDC Proposal for an Integrated Selective Information Processing System for the State of NY, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - NYSIIS Security Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - NYSIIS Security Review, Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - NYSIIS, Security System for Organized Crime Intelligence Capability, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - NYSIIS, "Six Hour Course on Elect. Data Processing" Conducted for Bankers Trust Company, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - NYSIIS, Standardized Data Elements for Criminal History Files, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - NYSIIS, Study of Crime Statistics in MA, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - NYSIIS - Systems Development Corporation Contract, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Obstruction of Drugs, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Off-Track Betting - Reports - Memos - Notes (1 of 2), 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Off-Track Betting - Reports - Memos - Notes (2 of 2 ), 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Organized Crime Committee Reports, Corresp., News Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Organized Crime in Canada, Federal- Provincial Conference - Commissioner G.B. McClellan - Report, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Organized Crime, Newsclippings, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Organized Crime, Photos from Case Files, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Organized Crime, Reports -Governor's Crime Control Program, Waterfront Commission of NY Harbor Press Releases, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Organized Crime Reports, Newsclippings, + Legislative Bills, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Organized Crime Research, 1964-1968; Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Organized Crime Today, Systems Analysist Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Organized Crime - Your Silent Partner" - by Louis Scalzo - Slide Presentation, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Oyster Bay Conference on Combatting Organized Crime, Agenda of Fourth Conference, Report "A Theory of Organized Crime Control: A Preliminary Statement", 1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Oyster Bay Conference, Correspondence about Programming and Invitation Declines, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Oyster Bay Conference, Governor Rockefeller Press Release, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Oyster Bay Conference on Organized Crime, Preliminary Reports and Notes, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Oyster Bay Conference Reunion, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Pits Commission on Organized Crime - Reports -Memos, 1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Plans for Development of Crime Control in the State of NY," Proposal and Research (1 of 2), 1969-1971; Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Plans for Development of Crime Control in the State of NY," Proposal and Research (2 of 2), 1969-1971; Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Police Force in France- Notes - Description, 1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Police Salary Data and Legislative Bills, 1966; Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Police Surveys and Outline for the Home Office Police Research and Planning Branch, Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Politics - Nixon Campaign - Election Brochures, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Preliminary Proposal for a Research Study on the Development and Use of Records in Correction and Parole, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - President Johnson Press Releases Concerning Crime, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - President Johnson -Speeches, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - President's Commission on Law Enforcement and Admin. of Justice -Advisory Panel - Meeting Notes, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - President's Commission of Law Enforcement and Admin. of Justice - "Bail, Summons and Preventative Detention", 1966 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - President's Commission on Law Enforcement and Admin. of Justice, Reports and Notes, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Press Releases about Criminal Justice by Rockefeller, Lindsay and NYC Police, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Press Releases and Bill Proposal from Gov. Rockefeller for a Department of Crime Control, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Prison Architecture, 1970 -1973 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Probation and Parole Conference, Corresp. and Reports, 1959 -1967; Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Proceedings of the Meetings of the Municipal Police Training Council, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Proposal for Creation of a Department of Crime Control in NYS, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Proposal for a National Organized Crime Intelligence Board Sent to Oyster Bay Conference Participants, ca. 1967 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Proposal for the Creation of a NYS Dept. of Justice, Corresp. and Press Release, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Proposed New England Regional Program Against Organized Crime, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Proposal - State Dept. of Crime Control - News Releases and Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Racial Violence - News Releases- Reports (1 of 2), 1967 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Racial Violence - News Releases - Reports (2 of 2), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Racial Violence - Notes - Releases - Articles, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Racial Violence -News Releases - Reports, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Racketeering and Labor an Economic Analysis" - Newsclippings - Waterfront Commission of New York Harbor Annual Reports, 1960-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Radio Interview by NYC Welfare Commissioner Dumpson and Report on the Status of Illegal Gambling Enforcement in NYC, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations of the Platform Advisory Committee to the Committee on Rules and Regulations, Republican Party, ca. 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Committee on Organized Crime of the Atlanta Commission on Crime and Juvenile Delinquency, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reports of the 5th Oyster Bay Conference on Combatting Organized Crime, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reports of the Governor's Committee on Gambling in CT and Report on the Ontario Police Commission, 1965; Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reports of the Select Bi-Partisan Committee on Off- Track Betting, Press Releases, Radio Interview and Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reports of the Special Legislative Committee to Investigate Certain Allegations Affecting the Legislative and Its Members, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Reports on the Two Oyster Bay Conferences, Press Releases, and Corresp., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Reports on Combating Organized Crime and Administration of Criminal Justice, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Reports on Gambling and Organized Crime in Baltimore, MD, 1961-1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Reports on Gambling Devices and Articles about Betting and Pinball Machines, 1957; 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Reports on Utilization of State Police to Combat Organized Crime and Correspondence about Organized Crime Conferences and Issues, 1958; 1961-1963; Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Republican Delegates-at-Large for the Constitutional Convention, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Rockefeller Articles in Fortune and Look, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Rockefeller Campaign, Issues and Memos, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Rockefeller Campaign - Literature, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Rockefeller and Empire State Plaza, 1979-1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller for President, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Rockefeller Institute Bulletin, 10th Anniversary, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Rockefeller Institute, Public Service Award Winners, 10th Anniversary Dinner, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Rockefeller Public Service Award Dinners, Programs, 1990; 1991; 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller Tax Estimates, News Release, 1970 July 20 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Rockefeller Telegram to Congressional Delegation, Draft and Press Release, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Security and Alarm Systems Newsclippings and Reports, 1965; 1968-1969; Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Six-City Study, A Survey of Racial Attitudes in Six Northern Cities: Preliminary Findings", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The Shame of Our Prisons, Panel Discussion-Report, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Special Committee to Study NYS's Correction System, Press Release Draft, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - State Dept. of Crime Control - Governor's Special Committee on Criminal Offenders - Public Hearing Reports, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - State Dept. of Crime Control, Governor's Special Committee on Criminal Offenders- Reports - Notes, 1966; Undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - State Dept. of Crime Control - News Releases - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - "State Governments and Organized Crime,", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - State-Law Enforcement Intelligence Units - Organization, Rules and Procedures, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Teaching Note of John Bliss "History of the Police Force" Lecture, 1965; Undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - "This is NYS" and Proposed Reorganization of the Executive Branch of NYS Gov't, 1959; Undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Transcript of CBS Reports: "Men in Cages", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wiretapping Reports and Newsclipping (1 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wiretapping Reports and Newsclippings (2 of 2), 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Other Public Service, Professional Associations and Organizations, 1952-2006; 7.5 cubic ft.
  This series consists of records from Lumbard’s other positions in public service, with professional associations, and other organizations. He worked as Chief Criminal Justice Consultant to the New Jersey State Legislature, 1967-1969, and an advisor to Charles McCurdy Mathias Jr. of Maryland during his successful 1968 Senate campaign. He was a member of several professional associates including: the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, the American Bar Association and the International Bar Association. He also worked in a wide variety of organizations during his professional career, including the New York City Police Foundation (trustee 1971-1991, chairman 1971-1974, 1977) and the New York State Maritime Museum (trustee 1969-1980). He was a member of the Citizen’s Crime Commission, the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, John Lindsay for Mayor, and the Republican National Committee, Task Force on Crime. This series contains such materials as: reports, press releases, meeting minutes, directories, new clippings, academic papers, press packets, newsletters, photos, memos, transcripts and notes.
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, Gifting of "View of Albany" by Richard Haas, Corresp. and Paperwork, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Bar Association Annual Meeting London/ Scotland Itinerary, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Bar Association, London Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Bar Foundation, "Survey of the Administration of Criminal Justice in the U.S. and Criminal Justice Higher Education," (1 of 2), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Bar Foundation, " Survey of the Administration of Criminal Justice in the U.S. and Criminal Justice Higher Education," (2 of 2), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Maritime History Project, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Judicial Conference of the 2nd Judicial Circuit of the U.S., 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arthur C. Logan Memorial Hospital Board of Trustees, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of NY, 1979; 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of NY, Conferences and Retreats, 1978; 1981; 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of NY, Correspondence Regarding Panel on "Bankruptcy Receives and Trustees", 1978-1980; 1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of NY, Drug Abuse Council Inc., "The Effects of the 1973 Drug Laws on the NYS Courts", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Grievance Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Library Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Association of the Bar of the City of New York, The Record, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., The Criminal Law Reporter, (1 of 3), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., The Criminal Law Reporter, (2 of 3), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., The Criminal Law Reporter, (3 of 3), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., The Criminal Law Reporter, (1 of 2), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., The Criminal Law Reporter, (2 of 2), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - California Crime Commission, California System of Criminal Justice, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Citizen's Crime Commission of NYC, 1979-1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, Certificate of Incorporation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, "Controlling Firearm Violence: Get the Gunmen Off the Street", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, "Crossroads on Crime", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, Newsletters, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, "Organization", 1978-1979 (Oversized 21)
  - Citizens Crime Commission of NYC, "Organization" - Volume 1, 1978-1979 (Oversized 21)
  - Citizen's Crime Commission of NYC, Press Kit and Correspondence, 1979-1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Citizens Summer Committee Reports and Summer in Our City, Report to Mayor Lindsay, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Citizens Union, A Citizen's Guide to Crime Control, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Clinton Hill Neighborhood Project, Inc. Proposed By Laws, and Certificate of Incorporation, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Columbia Law School Alumni Association Board of Directors Dinner Meeting, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Congressional Record Newsletter and Campaign Systems, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Council Against Crime, Member Directory, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Crime Commission of Philadelphia and Correspondence with E.R. Gomberg, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Crime Control Digest, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Bedford- Stuyvesant Study and the Organized Crime Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, "The Case for Federal Firearms Control", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council Grant Proposal, Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Memos, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Memos - Notes, 1972 April 14 -16 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Minutes-Proposals- News Releases, 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Notes and Related Materials, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, Notes and Related Materials, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, United Report, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Department of Justice Press Releases and Bulletin, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Department of Justice Statement by Henry E. Peterson about Wiretapping and Electronic Surveillance, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Downtown Association, Correspondence, Events, and Annual Report, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Downtown Association Membership Directories and Resignation Letter, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - East Side Republican Club, Testimonial Dinner, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - FBI Law Enforcement Bulletin Reprints, Articles about Police Forces, 1953; 1961-1963; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Home Office Police Research and Planning Branch Britain Correspondence and Notes, 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Illinois Law Enforcement Commission, 1970; Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Insurance Information Institute, Studies and Articles on Insurance and Crime, 1968-1969; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - International Assoc. of Chiefs of Police, Inc., Legal Points Newsletter, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - International Bar Association, International Bankruptcy Cooperation Project, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - International Legal Center Report on Criminal Justice in Columbia, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - J. Edward Lumbard Statement before the U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Criminal Law and Procedures, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: Committee to Re-Elect John Lindsay-Brochures- Reports- Notes (1 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: Committee to Re-elect John Lindsay Brochures, Reports, and Notes (2 of 2), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: Dept. of Justice-NYC-Notes-Reports-Campaign Papers, 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: Narcotics-News Releases, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: News Releases about NYC Police Dept., 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - John Lindsay for Mayor: Press Releases, Notes, Correspondence, 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - John Lindsay- Task Force on Corrections- Report, 1966 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Judge Edward Lumbard: Anglo-American Legal Conference Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Law Enforcement Task Force- Agenda- Reports (1 of 2), 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Law Enforcement Task Force- Agenda-Reports (2 of 2), 1965; Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Law Enforcement Task Force, Report to Mayor -Elect John V. Lindsay, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Life Magazine: Series on Organized Crime Correspondence and Notes, 1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lumbard Association Directory, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lumbard Association, Honorable Judge J. Edward Lumbard, 1955; 1978; 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lumbard-Maryland - Brewster Campaign, Election Brochures - Debate Transcription, 1966-1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lumbard-Maryland - Corrections, Probations, and Parole -Task Force Members, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mathias Campaign- Alcoholism-Report- Recommendations, 1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - MD- Mathias Campaign- Criminal Justice Platform, 1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - MD - Mathias Campaign- Federal Proposals- Notes, 1967-1968; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)